<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Audiowalk on Lennart Melzer</title>
    <link>http://lennart.github.io/categories/audiowalk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Audiowalk on Lennart Melzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2014 — Lennart Melzer; all rights reversed</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lennart.github.io/categories/audiowalk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>HOME STREET HOME</title>
      <link>http://lennart.github.io/product/homestreethomebs_de/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lennart.github.io/product/homestreethomebs_de/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interactive exhibition guide for an art project in Braunschweig, Germany (my hometown) by students of the local university of arts. x artists turn private to public and exhibit their appartments. Each exhibition site is presented on a stylized map of Braunschweig and accompained by an audiosnippet giving a brief description of the works found there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, who helped building &lt;strong&gt;Brave New Work&lt;/strong&gt; as well and is also studying at HBK Braunschweig (university of arts) took part in the exhibition. I helped conceptualizing the website, webapp and implemented the core structure for both. While Aaron took care of the content and design, I was mainly working on the maps used in the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used knowledge from the former audiowalk and stripped it to the bare minimum. It is a responsive single-page app working with geolocation and some javascript for interaction. I used Tilemill to produce a distinct look for the map, which was used as a poster design for advertising the exhibition in Braunschweig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>