<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Application on Lennart Melzer </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/application/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOME STREET HOME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/homestreethomebs_de/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/homestreethomebs_de/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interactive exhibition guide for an art project in Braunschweig, Germany (my hometown) by students of the local university of arts. x artists turn private to public and exhibit their appartments. Each exhibition site is presented on a stylized map of Braunschweig and accompained by an audiosnippet giving a brief description of the works found there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, who helped building &lt;strong&gt;Brave New Work&lt;/strong&gt; as well and is also studying at HBK Braunschweig (university of arts) took part in the exhibition. I helped conceptualizing the website, webapp and implemented the core structure for both. While Aaron took care of the content and design, I was mainly working on the maps used in the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used knowledge from the former audiowalk and stripped it to the bare minimum. It is a responsive single-page app working with geolocation and some javascript for interaction. I used Tilemill to produce a distinct look for the map, which was used as a poster design for advertising the exhibition in Braunschweig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brave New Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/bravenewwork_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/bravenewwork_info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An audiowalk through the center of berlin. Guiding visitors through a dozen of handpicked locations throughout referring to the theme of &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;. Places are narrated by an ironic voice, while walks between spots contain music and/or interviews with politicans, artists or plain workers regarding the current and past understanding of &amp;ldquo;what is work?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Sinja Krüger selected and elaborated on each spots text for about one year for her master thesis, recording, composition of music, interviews, cutting as well as the whole mobile web application has been built within about a month of hard work by a team of six people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine and I helped conceptualizing and building the mobile app which was planned to go to the apple store and ended up being a full-fledged statically built website that downloads all content onto visitors smartphones and runs completely offline for the duration (roughly 80 minutes) of the walk with just GPS turned on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m writing this is still an unfinished project concerning the web application as there are some bugs to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bewertungs Raster Anwendung</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/bra_materialkompass_de/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/bra_materialkompass_de/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a internal web application for a small group of people reviewing educational publications by a strict reviewing schema.
Reviews eventually get published on a website to aid teachers in selection educational material for their classes. Publication&amp;rsquo;s metadata is added by moderators and assigned to reviewers, quality controlled and then published via an external interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application was built based on Symfony 2 and features a complete workflow engine and a complex 8 tabbed form that tries to avoid usual the pains of editing lengthy, complex forms by visual hints of completeness rather than displaying the notorious error messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Export is done via exposing a JSON REST interface of the published reviews, which get picked up by a separate website that consumes reviews and displays them on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>artflakes.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/artflakes_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/artflakes_com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a shopping portal for art prints on-demand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a team of about 5 people we created a platform for photographers, illustrators, designers and even hobbyists to share and sell their art online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform also sported curated collections and additionally hosted vast libraries of different partners namingly national geographic, lonely planet images and bridgeman. Customers could buy their favourite images printed on varying media like poster, canvas or aluminium dibond which was manufactured on demand, first in germany then in north america as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was involved in conceptualizing the architecture, programming the print-product configurator, implementing the order-system and payment, building the activity feed and profile pages for the community, helped on templating, hosting and optimizing the caching system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main task behind the scenes however was eventually producing a toolchain for importing image libraries from all the partners we acquired and sanitizing and mapping metadata to the platform, including pregenerating thumbnails for the various listings and types of image display of a single product. The toolchain could be used without programming knowledge, but it sported a code editor that would allow running snippets of mapping code across a whole set of metadata for a certain partner that was stored before being imported into the main web-application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the company after it successfully maintained a constant revenue in early 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>grammophon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/grammophon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/grammophon/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;nifty frontend for &lt;del&gt;upcoming&lt;/del&gt; distributed, decentralized music management.
I tried hard, but it stayed a prototype, until it became abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I tried to reinvent something that was already there: &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/RJ/playdar-core&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;playdar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Try to grasp the idea behind &lt;strong&gt;playdar&lt;/strong&gt; first, being able to enter any artist/track combination and let playdar to the heavy lifting, in this case &lt;em&gt;get the nearest location from where you can play that song&lt;/em&gt;. Now combine this with your average music consumption and you might realize that there&amp;rsquo;s still a need for management. Something that &lt;strong&gt;playdar&lt;/strong&gt; itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t and &lt;em&gt;by design&lt;/em&gt; will not offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use &lt;strong&gt;iTunes™&lt;/strong&gt; for a reason, not because they love apple so much, but because it takes the load of music (and sadly recently media) management off your back. It&amp;rsquo;s elegant and easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you might ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with using iTunes?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with the &lt;em&gt;original idea&lt;/em&gt; behind &lt;strong&gt;iTunes&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s the current state of the &lt;em&gt;implementation&lt;/em&gt;. The concept of &lt;strong&gt;UNIX&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; command line applications applied to GUI-based apps, &amp;ldquo;let &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; application do &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; thing only and therefore do it &lt;strong&gt;extraordinary well&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, has seen it&amp;rsquo;s manifestation in the &lt;strong&gt;OPENStep&lt;/strong&gt; draft and current implementation in Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/strong&gt;. Your operating system should have &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; application to manage your contacts, &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; for managing your calendar, &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; for looking up words, &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; for viewing documents&amp;hellip; the list goes on. I appreciate Apple&amp;rsquo;s way of doing that and therefore I am using it, despite the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t like this company &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; a good job, but now we&amp;rsquo;re in the age of cloud-computing, constant internet connection and so on. Times have changed and what once was a simple &lt;em&gt;music player&lt;/em&gt; called iTunes, is now merely a host for random upcoming store shelves for the Apple company, selling and trying to manage everything not limited to music anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iTunes&lt;/strong&gt; has become the most bloated piece of software, avenged to the league of horrible things like &lt;strong&gt;eclipse&lt;/strong&gt; or the &lt;strong&gt;ICQ&lt;/strong&gt;-client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They failed at the heart of their current operating system, letting their former &lt;strong&gt;music player&lt;/strong&gt; become an operating system itself, throwing away the aforementioned concept of &amp;ldquo;do &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; thing and do it well&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should take into account that Apple is still a company and they deploy iTunes to &lt;strong&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/strong&gt; as well as Windows, so there is little reason why they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t put their main selling product (the iTunes-Store frontend) into their most used desktop application.&lt;br /&gt;
Fair enough, but I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; that simplicity, I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; that &amp;ldquo;do &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; thing and do it well&amp;rdquo; concept, especially for my music, but also for movies and maybe even music videos. I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; separate applications for that and I want each of them to network. That&amp;rsquo;s the main argument why I don&amp;rsquo;t want to use iTunes anymore.&lt;br /&gt;
Apple&amp;rsquo;s implementation of the DAAP-Protocol in iTunes is a joke. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to log into my iTunes-Store account to hear streamed music from the computer standing next to me.&lt;br /&gt;
Let&amp;rsquo;s repeat, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;playdar&lt;/strong&gt; let&amp;rsquo;s me hear the songs I want, from the nearest location that has it available&amp;rdquo;, so to put it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/jchris&#34;&gt;jchris&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; words &lt;a href=&#34;http://jchrisa.net/drl/_design/sofa/_show/post/Imagine-There-s-No-YouTube&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is not a technology problem, it&amp;rsquo;s a problem of imagination.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://playlick.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;playlick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the first part of the puzzle, but for me, it lacks a lot of stuff, mainly it lacks the desktop-application-feeling.&lt;br /&gt;
This project is an attempt to build exactly that, a &amp;ldquo;desktop-like&amp;rdquo; application serving just one purpose &lt;em&gt;managing the music you listen to, regardless of where it is physically located&lt;/em&gt;. Think of it as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://grooveshark.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grooveshark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but without the necessary coupling to the cloud. If there&amp;rsquo;s a song on your harddrive, then you can play it. If it is just available on youtube, then you can play it. I really like grooveshark, but the fact, that their database is far away from complete and predictably will always be, renders it useless to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I wanted it to be a Cocoa application, hence Mac OS X only.&lt;br /&gt;
Great, nothing wrong with that, Cocoa offers a great potential for building efficient and elegant applications, but it&amp;rsquo;s limited to one platform and still, Apple&amp;rsquo;s mashup-capabilities for Software development are kind of&amp;hellip;non-existant.&lt;br /&gt;
So currently this project is using Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Flash runtime, specifically the Flex 4 SDK and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/robotlegs/robotlegs-framework&#34;&gt;robotlegs-framework&lt;/a&gt;, but one should consider this a &lt;em&gt;proof-of-concept&lt;/em&gt;, an idea put into bits. In the future there may be native applications for each platform, but for now Flash serves well being available on all major platforms.&lt;br /&gt;
I started implementing &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/lennart/playdar-core/tree/crossdomain&#34;&gt;dynamic crossdomain.xml generation into playdar-core&lt;/a&gt; to allow flex applications to interface with your local playdar daemon. I use imlucas&amp;rsquo; as3playdar to interface with playdar and started to integrate blip.fm read-only support (which is one of the sources I wanted to have access to). At the current stage, simple search, blip.fm feed-loading, resolving, playlist building and playing works. That said, there is apparently nothing of the mentioned &lt;em&gt;managing&lt;/em&gt; capabilites integrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to keep a working up2date version hosted on the corresponding github-page for this project. You currently need a crossdomain-enabled built of playdar installed on you local computer and there are no prebuilt installers yet. One could pretty much say, this is still a developers project and not usable for anyone else. However, as soon as the crossdomain support is merged into playdar, using it should be as simple as clicking on the &amp;ldquo;Playdar.prefpane&amp;rdquo;, or the &amp;ldquo;Windar Installer&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;The Future™&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot resist to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://couchdb.apache.org/&#34;&gt;couchdb&lt;/a&gt; as the database for the music metadata, sadly there is currently no native erlang implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lucene.apache.org/java/docs/&#34;&gt;lucene&lt;/a&gt; or any other search-indexer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>clevershit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/clevershit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/clevershit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in university a friend of mine and I were fed up with the way we had to &lt;em&gt;manage&lt;/em&gt; aggregating all the documents, papers and all the stuff we got in university, to read and process. We took a look at what kinds of other communities were around and found a project called &amp;ldquo;clevershit&amp;rdquo;, which was a simple forum that had been setup by one of the students of computer science to gather all these information, and for others to exchange their thoughts. We strived to solve a problem, that was already solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driven by our half-god complex, of doing it better, doing it &lt;em&gt;the right way&lt;/em&gt;, we tried to build a platform based on the—back then hip and trendy—web application framework Ruby on Rails. An utterly over-engineered piece of software to build an utterly over-engineered platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to create a simple to use, highly flexible way of sharing and collaborating on &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; and never came to a close. All our prototypes never came across that stage, being a prototype. Essentially, what was missing, was the contact to other people, that would want to use it. We just tried to build a platform for a pretty narrow community, namely: us two. That is, we never bothered to ask what others might need, where the real pain points with the current solutions were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the other students were happy that &amp;ldquo;clevershit&amp;rdquo;, a forum, existed and, at least I had to learn that sometimes, worse is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A materials management system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/materials-mgmt-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/materials-mgmt-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just when I left school, a friend mine and I were asked to write a whole materials management system, or maybe just a part of it. We had some meetings, a company was founded, we invested in hardware, made some sketches for the later product, he took care of frontend designing and I went on to write a parser for a data interchange format that seemed to be quite common for such applications. That was about how far we got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point we realized, this is not going to work out. We underestimated the whole complexity and all the factors that had to be taken into account when writing software, that is not going to be used by tech-savvy people like we were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lesson in project planning, resource management, estimation of cost and time and so on. We halted everything and the product was never finished (at least not by us).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>