<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University on Lennart Melzer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/motivations/university/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University on Lennart Melzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2014 — Lennart Melzer; all rights reversed</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 UTC</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/motivations/university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Head tracking museum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/head-tracking-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/head-tracking-museum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tracking heads of people viewing a virtual exhibition. I worked on the OpenGL camera configuration to make everything look &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. you think you a looking through a window into a museum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minority WiiPort</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/minority-wiiport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/minority-wiiport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tracking hand gestures from a WiiMote mounted above a projection surface, letting you pinch &amp;amp; zoom images on the big screen from the tip of your fingers. I wrote the 3D rendering code using the &lt;strong&gt;OGRE&lt;/strong&gt; Game engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly most of the concepts we introduced here for gesture recognition, tracking of motion, and interaction with media, was later implemented in other software, most prominently the &lt;em&gt;pinch and zoom&lt;/em&gt; on the iPhone, which has been a key feature—though rather clumsy—within our own simple experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the actual coding of the software—which is pure &lt;code&gt;C++&lt;/code&gt; using some additions from the &lt;em&gt;Technical Report 1&lt;/em&gt; like smart pointers—this project was highly collaborative in version control via &lt;strong&gt;svn&lt;/strong&gt; and a complex build system using &lt;strong&gt;scons&lt;/strong&gt;. Our team consisting of six people had to coordinate our progress within the source code and build system while maintaining a working prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components of the project were: &lt;strong&gt;WiiMote&lt;/strong&gt; interfacing, gesture recognition using &lt;em&gt;Markov chains&lt;/em&gt;, logic dispatching, rendering and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly we did not completely agree on a License making it possible to distribute the code for &lt;em&gt;commercial&lt;/em&gt; use. Some of our colleagues were strong defenders of the &lt;strong&gt;GNU&lt;/strong&gt; ideology referring to &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; as in free speech, not as in beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>