<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Me on Lennart Melzer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/motivations/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Me on Lennart Melzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2014 — Lennart Melzer; all rights reversed</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 UTC</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/motivations/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation: Tidal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/tidal-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/tidal-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having just recently learned about live coding in general, I got to know Tidal, a domain specific pattern language for live coding written in Haskell. Struggling with the hitherto state of the documentation being sprinkled across the mailing list, single Markdown files on github and the wiki, I put up a Github page and organized/themed the content that was already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in contact with the developers of Tidal, I tried grasp the concepts behind Tidal to make the documentation both an easy start for beginners, a handy reference for users and a knowledge base for conceptually interested researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using only what github pages auto-build mechanism offers, I used twitter&amp;rsquo;s bootstrap in the sass variant and jekyll as the base for the page. I ordered the documentation into multiple chapters ranging from easy to complex and structured the list of available functions into logical groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added things like bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s scrollspy to help navigating a long list of menu entries and embedded syntax highlighting for the many code inlined snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>