<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Done on Lennart Melzer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/states/done/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Done on Lennart Melzer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2014 — Lennart Melzer; all rights reversed</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/states/done/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/the-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/the-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I moved into my apartment about three years ago, I wanted to &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; a table.  Passion seems to have kept me working on it until I finished it with a friend of mine using only wood, wood, glue and adjustable, metal feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that I necessarily needed one or am very knowledgable about woodcraft, I just found for wooden legs in my stairway, so I built a tabletop for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tabletop is built from two (originally three) planks—usually used for floors—cut into halves.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/img/thumbs/content/the-table-02.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;clean and empty, like never&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation: Tidal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/tidal-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/tidal-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having just recently learned about live coding in general, I got to know &lt;strong&gt;Tidal&lt;/strong&gt;, a domain specific pattern language for live coding written in &lt;strong&gt;Haskell&lt;/strong&gt;. Struggling with the hitherto state of the documentation being sprinkled across the mailing list, single &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; files on &lt;strong&gt;Github&lt;/strong&gt; and the wiki, I put up a &lt;em&gt;Github page&lt;/em&gt; and organized/themed the content that was already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in contact with the developers of &lt;strong&gt;Tidal&lt;/strong&gt;, I tried grasp the concepts behind &lt;strong&gt;Tidal&lt;/strong&gt; to make the documentation both an easy start for beginners, a handy reference for users and a knowledge base for conceptually interested researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using only what github pages auto-build mechanism offers, I used twitter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/strong&gt; in the sass variant and &lt;strong&gt;jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; as the base for the page. I ordered the documentation into multiple chapters ranging from easy to complex and structured the list of available functions into logical groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added things like bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s scrollspy to help navigating a long list of menu entries and embedded syntax highlighting for the many code inlined snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation is kickstarted and released to the community to be continuously improved. Since I started working on it, others have contributed Howtos for &lt;strong&gt;MIDI&lt;/strong&gt; integration and just recently the editor Integration was updated to prefer the &lt;a href=&#34;http://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom editor&lt;/a&gt; instead of &lt;a href=&#34;http://emacs.org&#34;&gt;emacs&lt;/a&gt; for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOME STREET HOME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/homestreethomebs_de/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/homestreethomebs_de/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interactive exhibition guide for an art project in Braunschweig, Germany (my hometown) by students of the local university of arts. x artists turn private to public and exhibit their appartments. Each exhibition site is presented on a stylized map of Braunschweig and accompained by an audiosnippet giving a brief description of the works found there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, who helped building &lt;strong&gt;Brave New Work&lt;/strong&gt; as well and is also studying at HBK Braunschweig (university of arts) took part in the exhibition. I helped conceptualizing the website, webapp and implemented the core structure for both. While Aaron took care of the content and design, I was mainly working on the maps used in the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used knowledge from the former audiowalk and stripped it to the bare minimum. It is a responsive single-page app working with geolocation and some javascript for interaction. I used Tilemill to produce a distinct look for the map, which was used as a poster design for advertising the exhibition in Braunschweig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stück 1998 — Manfred Werder — Pages 0761 - 0790</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/stuck_1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/stuck_1998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SuperCollider transcription and live playback of about thirty pages of Manfred Werder&amp;rsquo;s elegant &amp;ldquo;Stück 1998&amp;rdquo;. Lacking a real Piano for the performance at HOME STREET HOME, or at least something pianoesque, this was a few long hours effort to produce a sound installation supplementing Aaron&amp;rsquo;s visual exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing a day before the exhibition we will not have a piano for Lea to play a part of Manfred Werder&amp;rsquo;s composition, we decided to transcribe the sheet music (PDF) into a SuperCollider script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to its conceptual simplicity, &amp;ldquo;Stück 1998&amp;rdquo; could be easily parsed into a machine readable form. The composition is made up of succeeding notes of different (chosen by dice rolls) pitches played for six seconds, followed by six seconds rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I parsed the original document into an array of pitches which then were converted from german pitch notation into midi notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A minimalistic sine oscillator from SuperCollider and a simple Envelope was use for tone generation. We interlaced the pitch pattern with an infinite pattern of rests and set the tempo to be six seconds each bar, that&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SuperCollider script ran for four hours from my laptop (I luckily had with me for the exhibition) and audio was amplified to play out of the first floor window producing a sublime sound installation for Aaron&amp;rsquo;s visual exihibtion in front of the house. People passing by, or visiting the exihibition unconsciously took notice of the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During chats with visitors, many were trying to find a way to see &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; of the exihibition, being lured to believe there has to be something else. Though no one explicity talked about the music being played, it seemed to have the expected effect on recipients: being unwillingly exposed to it without being aware of being so. No one was able to categorize or even form an opinion about the music being good, or bad, still it had a subtle effect on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically we tried to leave the implementation as simple as possible, to keep with the spirit of the composition. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/lennart/fbb901667c19f66d3d4e&#34;&gt;Script&lt;/a&gt; is about three hundred and fifty lines of code, from which two hundred and fifty are just the formatted lines of pitches.  Thirty lines for converting pitches to midi notes, roughly eleven lines for the tone generator, five for the pattern, four for playback control (though we didn&amp;rsquo;t need to pause) and the rest are debug, or empty lines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfer haben Rechte</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/surfer_haben_rechte_de/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/surfer_haben_rechte_de/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IT-Team of the vzbv, my current employer, relaunched the website for the project &amp;ldquo;Surfer haben Rechte — Verbraucherrechte in der digitalen Welt&amp;rdquo; (Surfers have rights — consumer rights in the digital world). I helped building the infrastructure, migrate content, teach editors and customize the template.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rue Bunte</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/rue_bunte_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/rue_bunte_com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my holidays on crete, a friend of mine and I had some spare time left and rebuilt the website for an art-collective-backyard-something in Berlin Neukölln they run. It should be simple, both in its aesthetics and its caring for. I called a friend of mine at work in germany to setup FTP and the domain and we went online before returning to germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main goal was for Angelina to be able to add/edit events, pictures and content on her own. I decided to not use any content management system for it and helped her learn just a bit of markdown and handling ftp to publish a new version of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used wintersmith, a static site generator based on node.js which makes it easy to organize your content and also blazing fast in delivery, since it&amp;rsquo;s all static HTML/CSS in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bewertungs Raster Anwendung</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/bra_materialkompass_de/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/bra_materialkompass_de/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a internal web application for a small group of people reviewing educational publications by a strict reviewing schema.
Reviews eventually get published on a website to aid teachers in selection educational material for their classes. Publication&amp;rsquo;s metadata is added by moderators and assigned to reviewers, quality controlled and then published via an external interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application was built based on Symfony 2 and features a complete workflow engine and a complex 8 tabbed form that tries to avoid usual the pains of editing lengthy, complex forms by visual hints of completeness rather than displaying the notorious error messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Export is done via exposing a JSON REST interface of the published reviews, which get picked up by a separate website that consumes reviews and displays them on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>artflakes.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/artflakes_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/artflakes_com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a shopping portal for art prints on-demand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a team of about 5 people we created a platform for photographers, illustrators, designers and even hobbyists to share and sell their art online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform also sported curated collections and additionally hosted vast libraries of different partners namingly national geographic, lonely planet images and bridgeman. Customers could buy their favourite images printed on varying media like poster, canvas or aluminium dibond which was manufactured on demand, first in germany then in north america as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was involved in conceptualizing the architecture, programming the print-product configurator, implementing the order-system and payment, building the activity feed and profile pages for the community, helped on templating, hosting and optimizing the caching system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main task behind the scenes however was eventually producing a toolchain for importing image libraries from all the partners we acquired and sanitizing and mapping metadata to the platform, including pregenerating thumbnails for the various listings and types of image display of a single product. The toolchain could be used without programming knowledge, but it sported a code editor that would allow running snippets of mapping code across a whole set of metadata for a certain partner that was stored before being imported into the main web-application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the company after it successfully maintained a constant revenue in early 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head tracking museum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/head-tracking-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/head-tracking-museum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tracking heads of people viewing a virtual exhibition. I worked on the OpenGL camera configuration to make everything look &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. you think you a looking through a window into a museum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minority WiiPort</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/product/minority-wiiport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/product/minority-wiiport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tracking hand gestures from a WiiMote mounted above a projection surface, letting you pinch &amp;amp; zoom images on the big screen from the tip of your fingers. I wrote the 3D rendering code using the &lt;strong&gt;OGRE&lt;/strong&gt; Game engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly most of the concepts we introduced here for gesture recognition, tracking of motion, and interaction with media, was later implemented in other software, most prominently the &lt;em&gt;pinch and zoom&lt;/em&gt; on the iPhone, which has been a key feature—though rather clumsy—within our own simple experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the actual coding of the software—which is pure &lt;code&gt;C++&lt;/code&gt; using some additions from the &lt;em&gt;Technical Report 1&lt;/em&gt; like smart pointers—this project was highly collaborative in version control via &lt;strong&gt;svn&lt;/strong&gt; and a complex build system using &lt;strong&gt;scons&lt;/strong&gt;. Our team consisting of six people had to coordinate our progress within the source code and build system while maintaining a working prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components of the project were: &lt;strong&gt;WiiMote&lt;/strong&gt; interfacing, gesture recognition using &lt;em&gt;Markov chains&lt;/em&gt;, logic dispatching, rendering and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly we did not completely agree on a License making it possible to distribute the code for &lt;em&gt;commercial&lt;/em&gt; use. Some of our colleagues were strong defenders of the &lt;strong&gt;GNU&lt;/strong&gt; ideology referring to &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; as in free speech, not as in beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>